VIETNAM, 1965
1965년 베트남
Column, halt.
기둥, 정지.
It doesn't really matter what the war is for.
별로 중요하지 않습니다 전쟁은 무엇을 위한 것인가.
Someone's death becomes someone else's chance.
누군가의 죽음이 된다 다른 사람의 기회.
That's what war is.
그것이 바로 전쟁이다.
Looks like one of the Vietcong tunnels.
베트콩 터널 중 하나처럼 보입니다.
Moving in.
이사.
And my role was to be that death.
그리고 내 역할은 그 죽음이었습니다.
Just cannon fodder for someone else's rise.
그냥 대포 사료 다른 사람의 상승을 위해.
-How did it go? -It's been taken care of, sir.
-어떻게 됐어요? - 처리가 완료되었습니다, 선생님.
And the money in the safe?
그리고 금고에 있는 돈은요?
Baek will take it to you.
백현이가 데려가줄게
Clean it up right. No loose ends.
바로 청소하세요. 느슨한 끝은 없습니다.
Yes, sir. Understood.
네, 선생님. 이해했다.
It's done.
끝났습니다.
Mr. Jang!
장 씨!
Man, what the hell happened here?
대체 여기서 무슨 일이 일어난 거야?
Mr. Jang, are you all right? Are you hurt?
장 선생님, 괜찮으세요? 상처받았나요?
-Baek Kitae didn't show, right? -No, he never got off the ship.
- 백기태는 안 나왔죠? -아니요, 그 사람은 배에서 내리지 않았어요.
Well, let's start by tracking down Pyo Haksu first.
자, 추적부터 시작해 보겠습니다. 먼저 표학수.
We were just about to call in backup from the nearby army base.
우리는 방금 지원을 요청하려고 했어요 인근 군부대에서.
Search request, KCIA Agent Pyo Haksu.
검색요청, KCIA 요원 표학수.
-He showed up on his own. -You can't come in here!
-그가 직접 나타났어요. - 여기 들어오시면 안 돼요!
Move, asshole. I'm with the KCIA.
움직여, 멍청아. 나는 KCIA에 있어요.
-Hey! Let him through. -I said, move!
-여기요! 그를 통과시키세요. -움직이라고 했어!
Mr. Pyo Haksu!
표학수 선생님!
Come here, please.
이리 오세요.
How do you know who I am?
내가 누구인지 어떻게 알 수 있나요?
What's going on here?
여기서 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는 걸까요?
I'm Busan District Prosecutor Jang Geonyoung.
저는 부산지검입니다 장건영.
Okay. And?
좋아요. 그리고?
What brings the KCIA department head here?
KCIA 부서장이 왜 여기에 왔습니까?
I came to pick up the director.
감독님 데리러 왔어요.
-Director Hwang? -Yes, where is he?
-황 감독? -네, 그 사람은 어디 있어요?
Well, you killed him.
글쎄, 당신이 그를 죽였어.
You're under arrest
당신은 체포됩니다
for suspicion of Director General Hwang Gukpyeong's murder.
총장 의혹으로 황국평 살인사건.
Cuff him.
그에게 수갑을 채우세요.
Don't be ridiculous.
말도 안되는 소리하지 마십시오.
-Hey, wait. -Don't make a scene.
- 잠깐만요. -장난을 치지 마세요.
-Just hold on. -Come on.
-그냥 기다려요. -어서 해봐요.
No, stop! I'll do it myself.
아니, 그만해! 내가 직접 할게.
You sure you can handle this? What do you think you're doing?
당신이 이 일을 처리할 수 있다고 확신하나요? 지금 뭐하고 있는 것 같나요?
Quiet down. Let's go.
조용히 하세요. 갑시다.
WAR OF BLOOD
피의 전쟁
Mr. Baek, you're here.
백 선생님, 오셨어요.
What's going on?
무슨 일이야?
Prosecutors arrested Mr. Pyo
검찰, 표씨 구속
under suspicion of murdering Director Hwang.
의심을 받고 황 감독을 살해한 사건.
We're waiting on the autopsy to confirm the body's really Director Hwang.
부검을 통해 확인을 기다리고 있습니다 그 몸은 정말 황 감독님이군요.
Silence the press first.
먼저 언론을 침묵시키세요.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
Wait, sir. There's blood on your…
잠깐만요. 네 몸에 피가 묻어 있어…
I'm heading up to Seoul. Get the car ready.
저는 서울로 향하고 있어요. 차를 준비하세요.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
Hello?
안녕하세요?
-Hey, Soyeong. -Hi, Kitae.
-안녕, 소영. - 안녕, 키타에.
-Where's Daeil now? -Mr. Daeil?
-대일은 지금 어디에 있나요? -씨. 대일?
He was at the lab but left to take care of something.
그 사람은 연구실에 있었어 하지만 뭔가를 처리하기 위해 떠났습니다.
Why do you ask?
왜 물어보나요?
-Is something wrong? -Got it. I have to go.
- 무슨 문제라도 있는 걸까요? -알았어요. 나는 가야 해요.
Who was that?
그 사람은 누구였나요?
It's Kitae. He's looking for you.
키타에입니다. 그는 당신을 찾고 있습니다.
What for?
무엇 때문에?
I have no idea.
나는 모른다.
Mr. Pyo Haksu.
표학수 선생님.
Why did you kill him?
왜 그를 죽였나요?
Why did you kill Hwang?
왜 황씨를 죽였는가?
You keep crossing the line.
계속 선을 넘으시네요.
If you keep bulldozing ahead like that,
계속 그렇게 앞으로 밀고 나가면
how will you handle the consequences later?
어떻게 처리할 건가요? 결과는 나중에?
Just worried about you.
그냥 당신이 걱정됐어요.
You killed him. Didn't you?
당신이 그를 죽였어요. 그렇지 않았나요?
Did you see it?
봤어?
I saw him dead, shot through the eye.
나는 그가 눈에 총을 맞고 죽은 것을 보았습니다.
I told you. I dropped him off and went to buy cigarettes.
내가 말했잖아. 내가 그를 내려줬어요 그리고 담배를 사러 갔다.
Go ask at the store. How many times do I have to…
매장에 가서 물어보세요. 몇 번이나 해야 하나요...
So you're saying, while you were out buying cigarettes,
그래서 당신은 이렇게 말하고 있습니다. 네가 담배 사러 나가던 중에
Hwang ended up dead?
황씨 결국 죽었나?
What then?
그럼 어쩌지?
You think I killed him
넌 내가 그 사람을 죽였다고 생각하지?
and then went out for cigarettes?
그리고 담배를 피우러 나갔나요?
And the fire just happened to break out?
그런데 방금 불이 났어요?
Come on, Mr. Jang. That doesn't add up.
자, 장 씨. 그건 합산되지 않습니다.
And what motive could I have to kill him?
그리고 내가 그를 죽이려는 동기는 무엇입니까?
There's no motive.
동기가 없습니다.
Right.
오른쪽.
You went to buy cigarettes, Hwang died, and the fire broke out.
담배 사러 갔는데, 황 씨는 숨지고 불이 났다.
Baek Kitae was with you, wasn't he?
백기태도 함께 있었죠?
He was with you at the temple, right?
그 사람은 당신과 함께 성전에 있었지요?
Here it is.
여기 있습니다.
Look, that's Ikeda Yuji.
보세요, 이케다 유지입니다.
Tell me, what was the KCIA
말해봐 KCIA가 뭐였지?
doing with the yakuza in Osaka?
오사카에서 야쿠자와 뭐하고 있어?
That's classified. I can't tell you.
그건 기밀이에요. 나는 당신에게 말할 수 없습니다.
Classified, my fucking ass.
기밀이야, 빌어먹을 놈아.
Watch your language.
당신의 언어를 조심하세요.
I know you and Baek Kitae went to Japan
너랑 백기태랑 일본 간 거 다 알아
and sold meth there.
그곳에서 마약을 팔았어요.
Then, you passed the money to Hwang.
그리고 황씨에게 돈을 전달했습니다.
You did all the work,
당신은 모든 일을 했고,
but the bastard reaped the cash.
하지만 그 개자식은 현금을 거두었습니다.
That's why you and Baek Kitae killed him, isn't it?
그래서 너랑 백기태랑 그 사람을 죽였지, 그렇지?
Do you have proof? Do you?
증거가 있나요? 당신은?
Proof? Sure. I'll whip up a good one for you.
증거? 확신하는. 내가 당신을 위해 좋은 것을 준비하겠습니다.
-Wow. -You little…
-우와. - 너 꼬마야...
You do that.
당신은 그렇게합니다.
Hey.
여기요.
You like prison food? Huh?
감옥음식 좋아하시나요? 뭐?
-Jang. -Yes?
-장. -예?
A word?
한마디?
Goodness! What is it?
선량! 그것은 무엇입니까?
You should go.
당신은 가야합니다.
-Looks like you're in trouble. Go on. -Have a smoke while I'm gone.
-곤경에 처한 것 같습니다. 계속하세요. -나 없는 동안 담배 좀 피워요.
Geez.
이런.
BUSAN DISTRICT PROSECUTORS' OFFICE CASE RECORDS
부산지역 검찰 사건기록
So, Baek Kitae took over
그래서 백기태가 인수했다.
Jo Manjae's meth business?
조만재의 마약사업?
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
With Kang Daeil backing him?
강대일이 그를 지지하면서?
That's right.
좋아요.
And they killed Director Hwang?
그리고 그들이 황 감독을 죽였다고?
He had a gunshot wound
그 사람은 총상을 입었어요
to the face,
얼굴에,
through the right eye.
오른쪽 눈을 통해.
They shot him dead.
그들은 그를 총에 맞아 죽였습니다.
And set the place on fire
그리고 그 자리에 불을 질렀어요
to wipe out the evidence.
증거를 없애려고.
Sir.
선생님.
I'm going to
나는 갈 것이다
issue an arrest warrant for Baek Kitae.
백기태에 대한 구속영장을 발부하라.
If this goes wrong,
이것이 잘못되면,
the whole prosecution blows up.
검찰 전체가 터진다.
You realize that?
당신은 그것을 알고 있습니까?
-Yes. -Fucking hell.
-예. -젠장.
I'll make sure we get Pyo's confession.
표의 고백은 꼭 받아볼게.
This is the money
이것은 돈이다
Director Hwang had been skimming off behind your back.
황 감독은 횡설수설했다. 등 뒤에서.
Looks like his head wasn't the only thing he was thinning out.
머리만 그런 게 아닌 것 같더라 그는 쇠약해지고 있었다.
I believe he also had some land and buildings in his relatives' names.
내 생각엔 그 사람도 땅을 좀 갖고 있었던 것 같아 그리고 그의 친척 이름으로 된 건물들.
I'll check and report back as soon as I can.
확인해보고 다시 알려드리겠습니다 최대한 빨리.
And this.
그리고 이것.
It's Bae Geumji's notebook.
배금지님의 노트입니다.
Did you look?
봤어?
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
I did.
그랬어요.
And you saw my name?
그리고 내 이름 봤어?
I'm sorry, sir.
죄송합니다.
What do you want?
당신은 무엇을 원하세요?
I came to ask you to please reinvest this money with me.
물어보려고 왔어요 이 돈을 저에게 재투자해주세요.
If you'd let me, I'm sure I can use this as seed money
허락해 주신다면, 이거 꼭 종자돈으로 쓸 수 있을 것 같아
and multiply the returns by many times over.
그리고 수익을 곱해 보세요 여러 번에 걸쳐.
So you're saying,
그래서 당신은 이렇게 말하고 있습니다.
you want to do business with me?
나랑 거래할래?
The election is less than a year away.
선거가 1년도 채 남지 않았습니다.
I heard the President needs 70 billion won
대통령이 700억 필요하다고 들었는데
to secure another term for the good of the nation.
다른 기간을 확보하기 위해 국가의 이익을 위해.
I'll raise it.
내가 키울게.
How can I trust you?
내가 어떻게 당신을 믿을 수 있나요?
You don't have to trust me.
나를 믿을 필요는 없습니다.
Just give me a chance to prove what I can do.
나에게 기회를 줘 내가 무엇을 할 수 있는지 증명하기 위해.
I'll show you that even if you don't trust me, you can trust my money.
안 보여도 보여줄게 저를 믿으세요. 제 돈을 믿으셔도 됩니다.
I won't let you down, sir.
실망시키지 않겠습니다.
Go sit in that chair.
가서 저 의자에 앉으세요.
Go sit in it.
가서 앉으세요.
I heard Hwang went around telling everyone
황씨가 돌아다녔다고 들었어 모두에게 말하다
you were his pick for the next director,
당신이 차기 감독으로 뽑혔어요
and he took good care of you.
그리고 그는 당신을 잘 보살펴주었습니다.
And that made a lot of people jealous.
그리고 그것은 많은 사람들을 질투하게 만들었습니다.
Now that…
이제 그…
he's dead…
그는 죽었어…
shouldn't you be the one to take his place?
너는 그래야 하지 않니? 그 자리를 대신할 사람은?
Come to think of it,
생각해보면,
it's not all bad
다 나쁘지는 않아
for Baek Kitae that you're stuck in here.
여기 갇혀 있는 백기태를 위해.
Someone definitely murdered Hwang
누군가가 황씨를 죽인 것이 틀림없다
with a gun and burned down the place…
총으로 그 곳을 불태워버리고..
but you were out buying cigarettes.
그런데 당신은 담배를 사러 나갔잖아요.
Do you trust Baek Kitae?
백기태를 믿으시나요?
I don't know what kind of deal you made with him,
어떤 거래인지는 모르겠지만 당신은 그 사람과 함께 만든,
but think carefully.
하지만 잘 생각해보세요.
You and I both know
너와 나 둘 다 알아
who killed Hwang.
누가 황씨를 죽였는가.
PROSECUTORS' OFFICE
검찰청
STATEMENT
성명서
That day,
그날,
who else
또 누가
was at that temple…
그 절에 있었는데…
besides Hwang?
황씨 외에?
I want you to write down
적어주셨으면 합니다
the truth.
진실.
Do you want to rot in prison?
감옥에서 썩고 싶나요?
Baek Kitae becomes director general,
백기태 사무총장 취임
and you go to prison.
그리고 당신은 감옥에 갑니다.
-Excuse me, sir. -Yes?
-죄송합니다. -예?
Damn it.
젠장.
What's going on?
무슨 일이야?
The deputy chief prosecutor ordered the release of Pyo Haksu.
부장검사가 지시했다. 표학수 출시.
Please come with us, Mr. Pyo.
같이 가주세요, 표 선생님.
God, my legs…
맙소사 내 다리가...
Mr. Seo!
서 씨!
How can the prosecution hand over its investigative authority?
검찰이 어떻게 넘겨줄 수 있나요? 수사기관?
To the suspects, no less!
용의자에게, 그 이하도 아닙니다!
Who says you can do that?
누가 당신이 그런 일을 할 수 있다고 말합니까?
Hey!
여기요!
Get back inside.
안으로 돌아가세요.
You too. Get back inside.
너도. 안으로 돌아가세요.
DEPUTY CHIEF PROSECUTOR'S OFFICE PROSECUTOR SEO GIHO
차장검찰청 서기호 검사
What about you?
당신은 어떻습니까?
Who says they're suspects? You have no evidence.
누가 용의자라고 하던가요? 증거가 없습니다.
You said you didn't see Baek Kitae there.
거기서 백기태를 못 봤다고 하셨어요.
I'll arrest him on meth charges first.
먼저 마약 혐의로 그를 체포하겠습니다.
I'll get Kang Daeil to talk, charge Baek with drug offenses,
강대일한테 얘기 좀 해볼게 백씨를 마약범죄 혐의로 기소하고,
and then prove the murder!
그리고 살인을 증명하세요!
Now's the time to keep your head down.
이제 고개를 숙여야 할 때입니다.
They've even stripped our authority.
그들은 심지어 우리의 권위를 박탈했습니다.
You've got to hold on to your job if you want another chance later.
당신은 당신의 직업을 유지해야합니다 나중에 또 기회를 원하시면.
That bastard killed his own boss just to push meth!
그 새끼 마약을 밀기 위해 자기 상사를 죽였어!
All right?
괜찮은?
You know if we don't get him now, he'll become too big to catch!
지금 그 사람을 잡지 못한다면, 그 사람은 너무 커서 잡을 수 없을 거예요!
The order came from much higher up.
명령은 훨씬 더 높은 곳에서 왔습니다.
You understand what I'm saying?
내가 말하는 것을 이해합니까?
Well, who the hell is this higher-up?
그렇다면 이 고위층은 도대체 누구일까요?
Just watch your back for a while.
잠시만 등을 조심하세요.
THE BLUE HOUSE REPUBLIC OF KOREA
블루 하우스 대한민국
Na's really getting under Cheon's skin today, huh?
Na는 정말 지쳐가고 있어 오늘 천이 피부죠?
Tell me about it.
그것에 대해 말해주세요.
The President favors Cheon of the Security Service
대통령이 호의를 베푸는 경호원 천
over the secretariat these days, so…
요즘은 사무국을 넘어서서…
Mr. Na.
나 씨.
Why do you keep stirring up something that's already settled?
왜 자꾸 휘젓는 거야? 이미 해결된 일이요?
Didn't you hear me?
내 말 못 들었어?
It was the President's orders.
대통령의 명령이었습니다.
That's what you always say.
그게 당신이 항상 말하는 거예요.
It's getting hard to believe.
믿기가 점점 어려워지고 있습니다.
If you don't believe me, go ahead and check with him yourself.
당신이 나를 믿지 않는다면, 가서 직접 확인해 보세요.
Still, I serve him the same way you do, so how could you do that without a word--
그래도 나는 당신과 같은 방식으로 그를 섬깁니다. 그럼 어떻게 말 한마디 없이 그런 짓을 할 수 있겠어요?
Did you ask me before getting rid of Bae Geumji?
나한테 물어봤어? 배금지 없애기 전에?
You've got to be joking.
농담이겠죠?
-Bae Geumji? Me? -Anyway…
-배금지? 나? -어쨌든…
Keep tossing people out for no reason,
이유 없이 계속 사람을 쫓아내고,
and you might be the next one to go.
그리고 당신이 다음 사람이 될 수도 있습니다.
All right?
괜찮은?
You know, I'm just saying this for your own good.
있잖아, 난 그냥 이 말을 하는 거야 당신 자신의 이익을 위해.
Right, of course.
물론이죠.
Since you're so concerned, I'll bear that in mind.
너무 걱정해주셔서, 그 점을 명심하겠습니다.
Oh, right.
아, 그렇죠.
I heard you lost one of your subordinates.
부하 중 한 명을 잃었다고 들었습니다.
You must be devastated.
당신은 충격을 받았을 것입니다.
Perhaps, it's a sign
아마도 그것은 신호일 것이다.
you should watch your back too, Mr. Cheon.
천 선생님도 뒤통수 조심하세요.
Yeah, you should always be careful too.
응, 너도 항상 조심해야 해.
Take care of yourself.
몸 조심하세요.
As you know, I don't ask anyone…
아시다시피 저는 아무한테도 안 물어봐요…
before I get rid of someone.
내가 누군가를 없애기 전에.
It looks like there's a leak.
누출이 있는 것 같습니다.
Any idea who?
누구인지 아세요?
Jang Geonyoung knew we went to Japan.
장건영은 우리가 일본에 간 걸 알고 있었다.
And what we went there for.
그리고 우리가 거기에 간 이유.
So what did you tell him?
그래서 그 사람에게 뭐라고 말했어요?
Well, what else? I said it was classified.
글쎄, 또 뭐야? 기밀이라고 하더군요.
Did he say anything else?
그 사람이 다른 말이라도 했나?
He was sure you're the one who killed Hwang.
그 사람은 당신이 바로 그 사람이라고 확신했어요 누가 황씨를 죽였는가.
How did your meeting with Cheon go?
천씨와의 만남은 어땠나요?
How much…
얼마나…
did you tell Cheon?
천이한테 말했어?
What do you mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
He looked like he knew everything.
그는 모든 것을 알고 있는 것처럼 보였습니다.
I didn't tell him you killed Hwang.
나는 그에게 당신이 황씨를 죽였다고 말하지 않았습니다.
Like we agreed,
우리가 동의한 것처럼,
I just said he died in a fire.
방금 그가 화재로 사망했다고 말했습니다.
Which is true. He did die in a fire.
사실입니다. 그는 화재로 사망했습니다.
Well, doesn't matter.
글쎄요, 상관없습니다.
He didn't really seem to care.
그는별로 신경 쓰지 않는 것 같았습니다.
Yeah?
응?
But how did Jang Geonyoung know?
그런데 장건영은 어떻게 알았을까?
We got a rat or what?
쥐가 있거나 뭐야?
Did you find Baek Kitae?
백기태를 찾았나요?
He's nowhere to be found.
그는 어디에도 없습니다.
He hasn't been home,
그 사람은 집에 안 갔어요.
and the KCIA's keeping their mouths shut.
그리고 KCIA는 입을 다물고 있습니다.
What about the scene?
현장은 어떻습니까?
All we found were some bullet casings.
우리가 찾은 것은 총알 탄피뿐이었습니다.
Everything burned to a crisp.
모든 것이 바삭바삭하게 타버렸습니다.
There's no evidence left.
증거가 남아 있지 않습니다.
But, sir, is it really okay for us to keep doing this here…
그런데 선생님, 정말 그렇습니까? 여기서 계속 이 일을 해도 괜찮습니다…
I mean, there's nothing left to dig into,
즉, 더 이상 파헤칠 것이 아무것도 없습니다.
and if the deputy chief finds out, he'll rip into us.
그리고 만약 부국장이 그 사실을 알게 된다면, 그는 우리를 찢어 놓을 것입니다.
What about Kang Daeil?
강대일은요?
Any word from him?
그 사람한테서 어떤 소식이라도 있었나요?
When are the materials from Japan getting here?
재료는 언제쯤 되나요 일본에서 여기로 오나요?
We'll never make quota with what's left.
우리는 남은 것으로 할당량을 만들지 않을 것입니다.
Ms. Baek.
백 씨.
Come on, take a break.
자, 좀 쉬세요.
All right.
괜찮은.
Hope this tastes okay.
맛이 괜찮기를 바랍니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Mmm…
음…
-It's good. -Wait.
-좋습니다. -기다리다.
How are you so beautiful?
어쩜 그리 아름답나요?
Oh, please!
아, 제발!
Come on, stop.
어서, 그만해요.
Any word from your brother?
형한테서 어떤 소식이라도 있었나요?
Who cares?
누가 신경쓰나요?
He made one lousy call and hasn't shown his face since.
그 사람이 형편없는 전화를 한 번 했어 그리고 그 이후로 얼굴을 보여주지 않았습니다.
What's that? Didn't you say no one else was here?
그게 뭐야? 말하지 않았나요? 여기 또 아무도 없었어?
Who'd be here this late?
누가 이렇게 늦게 여기 올까요?
Sir.
선생님.
Hi, Kitae.
안녕, 키타에.
God, speak of the devil.
하나님, 악마에 대해 말씀해 주십시오.
Anyway, Kitae.
어쨌든, 키타에.
What are you doing here?
여기서 뭐하는거야?
What are you two doing here alone? It's late.
너희 둘은 뭐니? 여기서 혼자 하는 거야? 늦었어.
I had to finish up the books.
나는 책을 마무리해야했다.
Kitae.
키타에.
Gosh, this isn't what it looks like.
맙소사, 이건 아닌 것 같군요.
Yeah.
응.
Soyeong, give us the room.
소영 씨, 방 좀 주세요.
-Why? -I need to talk to Daeil.
-왜? -대일씨한테 얘기 좀 해야겠어요.
Okay.
좋아요.
You said you were going to Japan, but I didn't hear from you
일본에 간다고 하더군요. 하지만 난 너한테서 소식을 듣지 못했어
so I was worried.
그래서 걱정이 됐어요.
Everything okay while I was gone?
내가 없는 동안 괜찮았나요?
Of course, sir. Everything was fine.
물론이죠, 선생님. 모든 것이 괜찮았습니다.
So, you need to talk to me about something?
그러니까 나랑 얘기 좀 해야 해 뭔가에 대해?
Have a seat.
앉으세요.
Okay.
좋아요.
Daeil.
대일.
What do you think is the most basic virtue a person should have?
가장 기본적인 덕목은 무엇이라고 생각하시나요? 사람이 있어야 해?
I've never really thought about it.
나는 그것에 대해 정말로 생각해 본 적이 없습니다.
Then think about it now.
그렇다면 지금 생각해 보세요.
Loyalty?
충의?
Sure, loyalty's important.
물론, 충성도가 중요합니다.
But you know what I think?
하지만 내가 어떻게 생각하는지 알아?
I think it's shame.
부끄러운 일인 것 같아요.
Shame?
창피?
The people I hate most are the shameless ones.
내가 가장 싫어하는 사람은 바로 뻔뻔한 놈들.
Those who have no sense of shame at all.
부끄러움이 전혀 없는 분들입니다.
They're the ones who stab you in the back.
그들은 당신의 등을 찌르는 사람들입니다.
They wag their tails in front of you,
그들은 당신 앞에서 꼬리를 흔들고 있습니다.
acting like they'd do anything for you.
그들이 당신을 위해 무엇이든 해줄 것처럼 행동합니다.
But when it really counts, they betray you.
하지만 정말 중요한 순간에는 그들은 당신을 배신합니다.
They do it because they have no shame.
그들은 부끄러움이 없기 때문에 그렇게 합니다.
But if you don't have shame,
하지만 부끄러움만 없다면
how are you any different from an animal?
너는 동물과 뭐가 다른데?
Am I right?
내가 맞나요?
Hey.
여기요.
You got anything to say to me?
나한테 할 말 있어?
You're colluding with Jang Geonyoung, aren't you?
당신은 공모하고 있습니다 장건영이랑 같이 있지?
If you do this, we can't work together.
이렇게 하면 우리는 함께 일할 수 없습니다.
If you really can't trust me…
정말 나를 믿을 수 없다면…
just shoot me.
그냥 나를 쏴.
Why do you look like that?
왜 그렇게 보이나요?
Is Director Hwang dead?
황 감독은 죽었나요?
Did Baek Kitae tell you?
백기태가 말했지?
I can't do this anymore.
나는 더 이상 이것을 할 수 없습니다.
If even Hwang can be snuffed out just like that…
황씨도 그럴 수 있다면 그렇게 터져버렸어…
That's why you need to do this right,
그렇기 때문에 이 일을 제대로 해야 합니다.
if you don't want Baek Kitae to kill you.
백기태가 널 죽이는 게 싫다면.
If he finds out you're my mole,
그 사람이 당신이 내 두더지라는 걸 알게 된다면,
you think he'll let you get away with it?
그 사람이 당신을 그냥 놔둘 것 같나요?
This only ends when Baek Kitae's caught.
백기태가 잡히면 끝나는 일이다.
And that's how you stay alive.
그리고 그것이 당신이 살아남는 방법입니다.
This is the last time.
이번이 마지막입니다.
When's the deal?
거래는 언제 되나요?
I need your word.
당신의 말이 필요합니다.
When is it?
언제입니까?
Tonight at 10:00 p.m.,
오늘 밤 10시,
the Mangeum will rendezvous in international waters
만금이 만날 것이다 국제 해역에서
with a Japanese vessel loaded with meth ingredients,
일본 선박과 함께 메스 성분이 가득 들어있고,
according to my source.
내 출처에 따르면.
One team will hit the Mangeum,
한 팀은 만금을 치고,
and the other will raid the gang's base, the meth lab, at the same time.
다른 한 명은 갱단의 기지를 습격할 것이고, 동시에 마약 연구실.
-Team Mangeum. -Team Mangeum!
-만금팀. -만금팀!
-Team Meth Lab!
-팀 메스 연구소!
Now, Team Meth Lab.
이제 Team Meth Lab.
This is Baek Soyeong.
백소영 입니다.
She's a key figure who handles the gang's accounts.
그녀는 주요 인물입니다 갱단의 회계를 처리하는 사람.
She must be arrested on site tonight.
그녀는 오늘 밤 현장에서 체포되어야 합니다.
-Yes, sir! -Busan Prosecutors Narcotics Unit!
-네, 선생님! -부산검찰 마약수사대!
-We got this!
- 우리는 이것을 얻었다!
We got this!
우리는 이것을 얻었습니다!
Let's go.
갑시다.
All right, we're moving in.
알았어, 우리는 이사 간다.
These bastards. They're all hiding, huh?
이 놈들. 다들 숨어있죠?
Hey, you! Over there! Don't move!
이봐, 너! 저기요! 움직이지 마세요!
You bastard!
이 개자식!
Get out here!
여기서 나가세요!
Hey! Get out here now!
여기요! 지금 당장 여기서 나가세요!
-What the hell? -Get them!
-대체 뭐야? - 가져와!
Mr. Jang! Are you all right?
장 씨! 괜찮으세요?
What are you doing? Get in there! Go!
뭐하세요? 거기 들어가세요! 가다!
Go! Move it!
가다! 움직여!
-You damn… Hey! -Let's go!
- 젠장… 이봐요! -갑시다!
Come here!
이리 오세요!
Hey, you! Come here!
이봐, 너! 이리 오세요!
Stand down, asshole!
물러서라, 이 새끼야!
Get back here!
여기로 돌아가세요!
Get back here, you bastard!
여기로 돌아가라, 이 개자식아!
Got you now, you little shit.
이제 알았어, 이 새끼야.
You asshole, why do you keep following me?
이 멍청아, 왜 자꾸 나를 따라오는 거야?
Come on, let's go! Come on!
자, 가자! 어서 해봐요!
Fine. Let's go, jackass.
괜찮은. 가자, 멍청아.
Hey, man!
이봐, 친구!
That was a blank.
그것은 공백이었습니다.
Now it's live rounds.
이제 라이브 라운드가 시작되었습니다.
-Kim! -Yes, sir!
-킴! -네, 선생님!
Round them up and find the drugs!
그들을 모아 마약을 찾아보세요!
-You heard him! -Yes, sir!
- 그 사람 말 들었잖아! -네, 선생님!
Search for the drugs! Start searching for the drugs!
마약을 찾아보세요! 마약 검색을 시작하세요!
Hey, eat shit!
야, 똥 먹어!
There!
거기!
Back off! Go!
물러서세요! 가다!
Hey! Back off!
여기요! 물러서세요!
Back off!
물러서세요!
Fuck.
못쓰게 만들다.
Damn it, why do you keep following me?
젠장, 왜 자꾸 따라오는 거야?
Stop! Stop it!
멈추다! 그만해요!
KOOC, MENT, FUNKY STRIKE
KOOC, MENT, 펑키 스트라이크
-What? -Sir.
- 뭐? -선생님.
What is this? It's not here?
이게 뭔가요? 여기는 아니지?
-No, it's not… -It's not?
-아니, 그렇지 않아… - 그렇지 않나요?
Check deeper inside.
더 안쪽을 확인해 보세요.
Damn it.
젠장.
-What about here? No? -No.
- 여기는 어때요? 아니요? -아니요.
Mr. Jang!
장 씨!
There's only stuff like this.
이런 내용밖에 없습니다.
Is Baek Soyeong not here?
백소영 씨는 없나요?
She's not here.
그녀는 여기 없어요.
-Come on, open them. -Damn it.
-어서 열어보세요. -젠장.
Check this one. This one.
이것을 확인하세요. 이것.
Damn it. These are all just watches.
젠장. 이것들은 모두 시계일 뿐입니다.
Where's Kang Daeil?
강대일은 어디 있지?
Hey! You shithead.
여기요! 이 멍청아.
Where's Baek Soyeong?
백소영은 어디있나요?
Who's that?
저 사람은 누구야?
I have no idea.
나는 모른다.
I said, where's Baek Soyeong?
백소영은 어디 있어요?
I don't know.
모르겠습니다.
I really don't know!
정말 모르겠어요!
Damn it!
젠장!
You don't have to give me this.
나에게 이것을 줄 필요는 없습니다.
I'll never…
나는 결코…
I won't ever cross you again, sir.
다시는 당신을 거스르지 않겠습니다, 선생님.
If you really can't trust me…
정말 나를 믿을 수 없다면…
just shoot me.
그냥 나를 쏴.
I'm sorry, sir.
죄송합니다.
Lay low for a while.
잠시 동안 누워 있으십시오.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
Kang Daeil.
강대일.
Finding Kang Daeil comes first!
강대일 찾기가 우선!
Stake out his family's homes
그의 가족의 집을 측설하다
and coordinate with local precincts to post officers at every terminal.
지역구와 조율하여 모든 터미널에 직원을 배치합니다.
Now!
지금!
-Yes, sir! -Will do!
-네, 선생님! - 그럴게요!
We're from the Inspection Division.
우리는 검사과 출신이에요.
Everyone, hands off your desks.
여러분, 책상에서 손을 떼세요.
Who the hell are you?
도대체 당신은 누구입니까?
We got a tip
팁이 있어요
that the investigators here resold the drugs they seized.
여기 조사관들이 압수한 마약을 재판매했습니다.
What the hell are you talking about?
도대체 무슨 소리를 하는 거야?
Look, who said that? What tip?
봐, 누가 그런 말을 했어? 무슨 팁?
Senior Investigator Kim Jeongwon.
김정원 선임연구원.
Investigator Oh Yejin, right?
오예진 조사님 맞죠?
Please come with us, the two of you.
두 분도 함께 가주세요.
Don't move an inch.
1인치도 움직이지 마세요.
I'll be back in a minute.
잠시 후에 돌아올게요.
Move!
이동하다!
Get everything.
모든 것을 얻으십시오.
Geez, why are you doing this?
이런, 왜 이러는 걸까요?
PROSECUTOR SEO GIHO
서기호 검사
You're shutting down the Narcotics Unit because those dealers are giving you shit?
마약수사대를 폐쇄합니다 그 딜러들이 너한테 똥을 주고 있으니까?
It's the chief's orders!
대장의 명령이다!
So we're going to let Baek Kitae toy with the prosecution like this?
그래서 우리는 백기태를 보자. 검찰을 이렇게 가지고 놀아?
It's just until the inspection is over!
검사가 끝날 때까지만이에요!
End of discussion!
토론 끝!
Just don't come into the office, and keep your head down for a while!
그냥 사무실로 들어오지 마세요. 그리고 잠시 동안 고개를 숙이고 계세요!
I'll pull your people out of the Inspection Division somehow!
내가 네 사람들을 끌어당길게 어떻게든 검사과에서 나가세요!
All right, fine!
알았어, 알았어!
I'll go pay the chief a visit
내가 국장을 방문하러 갈게
and talk to him myself!
그 사람과 직접 얘기해 보세요!
Hey!
여기요!
Oh!
오!
Hey, get back inside.
이봐요, 다시 안으로 들어가세요.
Get back inside!
다시 안으로 들어가세요!
Hey.
여기요.
You think I haven't tried?
내가 시도하지 않았다고 생각하시나요?
The man didn't even flinch when I stood up to him and threatened to quit!
내가 일어섰을 때 그 사람은 꼼짝도 하지 않았어 그에게 그만두겠다고 위협했습니다!
What the hell do you think you can do?
도대체 당신이 무엇을 할 수 있을 것 같나요?
Unless you want your people to suffer more, keep your head down.
당신이 당신의 사람들을 원하지 않는 한 더 많은 고통을 받으려면 고개를 숙이십시오.
Those bastards are coming at us hard!
그 놈들이 우리에게 세게 다가오고 있어요!
-But I-- -Jang.
-하지만 난-- -장.
Stop trying to bulldoze through.
밀어붙이려는 시도를 중단하세요.
Think, for God's sake.
생각해 보세요, 제발요.
Baek's got Chief Cheon backing him.
백씨는 천과장이 그를 지지하고 있다.
Who have you got?
당신은 누구를 가지고 있습니까?
If you're going to go after them, you've got to match their weight at least!
그 사람들을 뒤쫓으러 갈 거라면, 최소한 그 사람의 몸무게와 일치해야 해요!
You complete idiot.
완전 바보야.
"The Prosecution, walking the straight path,
"검찰, 곧은 길을 걷고,
upholding principle!"
원칙을 지켜라!"
Hey, get back inside.
이봐요, 다시 안으로 들어가세요.
You too. Get back inside.
너도. 안으로 돌아가세요.
Hope you don't mind me calling you in while I do this.
당신이 나를 신경 쓰지 않기를 바랍니다 내가 이 일을 하는 동안 당신을 불러요.
I've got to take good care of the President,
잘 챙겨야 겠어요 대통령의,
but I never get time to hit the field.
하지만 나는 현장에 나갈 시간이 없습니다.
Not at all, sir.
전혀 그렇지 않습니다.
Don't worry about it.
걱정하지 마세요.
I hear Chief Cheon's been meddling with prosecutorial authority?
천과장님이 끼어들었다고 들었어 검찰권으로?
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
It seems he ordered the KCIA
KCIA에 지시한 것 같아
to investigate Director Hwang's case directly.
조사하다 황 감독의 사건이 직접적으로.
Go on.
계속하세요.
The truth is,
진실은,
one of our prosecutors in the Narcotics Unit
우리 검사 중 한 명 마약수사대에서
was investigating Baek Kitae,
백기태를 조사하던 중,
the KCIA department head who's in charge of Hwang's case right now,
KCIA 담당 부서장 지금 황씨의 경우는
for running a meth operation.
마약 작업을 실행하기 위해.
I know it's presumptuous of me to say this to you,
나도 그게 나에 대한 주제넘은 짓이라는 걸 알아 당신에게 이 말을 하려고,
but the fact that the Chief of the Presidential Security Service
하지만 수석이라는 사실은 대통령경호실의
-would back someone like Baek-- -Chief Cheon is
-백씨 같은 사람을 지지할 텐데-- -천 과장은
covering for a meth peddler?
마약 행상인을 덮고 있습니까?
OSAKA, JAPAN
일본 오사카
Looks like I'm the last one.
제가 마지막인 것 같습니다.
I'm sorry to keep you waiting, Father.
기다리게 해서 죄송해요, 아버지.
So,
그래서,
how many factories do we have left?
공장이 몇 개나 남았나요?
We've still got a couple left, but the police are watching them closely.
아직 한두개 남았는데, 하지만 경찰은 그들을 면밀히 감시하고 있습니다.
There's no telling how long they'll last.
얼마나 오래 지속될지는 알 수 없습니다.
Everyone says the meth trade's finished in Japan.
다들 마약거래라고 하던데 일본에서 끝났다.
Even the Shibazaki clan seems to be pulling out of the business.
심지어 시바자키 일족도 보인다. 사업을 그만두게 됩니다.
Finished? Hardly.
완성된? 거의 ~ 아니다.
Addicts are still crawling all over Japan looking for drugs.
중독자는 여전히 크롤링 중입니다. 일본 전역에서 마약을 찾고 있습니다.
We just need to build a new plant in Korea,
우리는 구축만 하면 돼 한국의 새로운 공장,
and the problem's solved, Father.
문제는 해결됐어요, 신부님.
In Korea, we can easily bring in raw materials from Hong Kong or Taiwan,
한국에서는 쉽게 반입이 가능해요 홍콩이나 대만산 원료,
and enforcement is weak.
그리고 집행력이 약해요.
It's the ideal place to produce meth.
그곳은 필로폰을 생산하기에 이상적인 장소입니다.
Look, just when is this new plant supposed to be built?
봐, 이 새로운 식물은 언제쯤이야? 지어져야 한다고?
Chasing pipe dreams like a fool only puts the clan at risk.
바보처럼 헛된 꿈을 쫓아 클랜을 위험에 빠뜨릴 뿐입니다.
The meth market grows every year,
마약시장은 매년 성장하고 있으며,
and it's still our biggest source of funds.
그리고 그것은 아직도 우리의 가장 큰 자금원입니다.
Giving that up too easily
너무 쉽게 포기해
is what would put the clan at risk.
클랜을 위험에 빠뜨리는 것입니다.
The real foolishness, don't you think?
진짜 어리석음이 아닌가?
You're forgetting your place, you Chosenjin!
당신은 당신의 자리를 잊어버리고 있어요. 너 초센진!
How dare you!
감히!
I hope
나는 바란다
you're not making a foolish choice.
당신은 어리석은 선택을 하고 있지 않습니다.
Because giving a fool a chance is
바보에게 기회를 주는 것은
just as foolish.
마찬가지로 어리석은 일이다.
SEOUL, KOREA
한국 서울
Seems like you've taken quite a liking to Baek Kitae.
취하신 것 같네요 백기태를 꽤 좋아한다.
You forgave him for taking out Director Hwang.
당신은 그를 용서했습니다 황 감독을 빼내기 위해서다.
He's the one who killed Hwang?
황씨를 죽인 사람이 그 사람인가?
You didn't know?
몰랐어요?
I heard he died in a fire.
화재로 사망했다는 소식을 들었습니다.
Am I mistaken?
내가 착각한 걸까?
Well, there was a fire, but…
뭐, 불은 났지만…
You just don't care, do you?
당신은 그냥 상관 없어, 그렇지?
The thing about greedy people is, they're quick to get stupid.
탐욕스러운 사람들의 문제는, 그들은 빨리 바보가 됩니다.
Doesn't matter to me who sits in that seat.
나에겐 상관없어 그 자리에 앉은 사람.
Apparently, you're the one who's taken a liking to him.
분명히 당신은 그 사람입니다 그 사람을 좋아하게 된 사람.
Is it because he's good-looking?
그 사람이 잘생겼기 때문일까요?
What if something happens to Baek?
백현에게 무슨 일이 생기면 어쩌지?
Do you have an alternative?
대안이 있나요?
Why?
왜?
Do you not trust him?
당신은 그를 믿지 않습니까?
I don't trust people.
나는 사람을 믿지 않습니다.
I trust what I hold.
나는 내가 갖고 있는 것을 신뢰합니다.
And that's why you're the one who scares me most.
그래서 당신은 나를 가장 무서워하는 사람.
Baek cares a lot about his younger siblings.
백현이 신경 많이 써 그의 동생들에 대해서.
Especially his brother, Baek Kihyun.
특히 그의 동생 백기현.
He's a Korea Military Academy graduate, just like you.
육군사관학교 졸업생입니다. 당신처럼.
-A Military Academy graduate? -Yes.
- 육군사관학교 졸업생이요? -예.
His brother is his weak spot.
그의 형은 그의 약점이다.
That's what concerns me.
그것이 제가 걱정하는 것입니다.
Move to the sides!
옆으로 이동하세요!
-Hey, walk straight. -Private First Class Hong Jihwan!
-야, 똑바로 걸어. - 일등병 홍지환!
I'm pushing you from behind.
뒤에서 밀어주고 있어요.
Thank you. Thank you, sir!
감사합니다. 감사합니다!
-Really? -I've got this, sir.
-정말? - 이거 갖고 있어요, 선생님.
The hell you do, damn commie.
젠장, 빌어먹을 빨갱이.
Hey!
여기요!
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
Hong must've twisted his ankle, sir.
홍 씨가 발목을 삐었나 봐요.
That's why he tumbled down the hill.
그 때문에 그는 언덕 아래로 굴러떨어졌다.
Please don't worry about him.
그 사람에 대해서는 걱정하지 마세요.
Get up.
일어나세요.
Take off your pack.
배낭을 벗으세요.
I've got this, sir.
제가 이걸 갖고 있어요, 선생님.
This is an order.
이것은 명령입니다.
We've got a goddamn commie and a chickenshit.
우리에겐 빌어먹을 빨갱이가 있어 그리고 닭똥.
-That goddamn idiot. -What a great fucking unit.
- 그 빌어먹을 바보. - 정말 대단한 유닛이군요.
Private Hong, it's not your watch yet.
홍 일병, 아직 당신의 시계가 아닙니다.
What are you doing here so early, sir?
선생님, 이렇게 일찍 여기서 뭐 하시나요?
Huh?
뭐?
I was cold.
나는 추웠다.
Everyone's asleep, right?
다들 자고 있는 거 맞죠?
Yes, sir. They are.
네, 선생님. 그렇습니다.
Good work.
잘했어요.
MILITARY POLICE
군경찰
One, two.
하나, 둘.
Look at this little shit. Did you just dodge?
이 작은 것 좀 봐. 방금 피했지?
Goddamn it.
젠장.
How the hell did you let this happen?
도대체 어떻게 이런 일이 일어나도록 방치한 걸까요?
I'm sorry, sir!
죄송해요 선생님!
Both our jobs are on the line if we don't contain this.
우리 두 직업 모두 위태로워 우리가 이것을 포함하지 않는다면.
-You hear me? -Yes, sir!
- 내 말 들려요? -네, 선생님!
Keep checking on the injured until sunrise,
부상자 계속 확인 일출까지,
and if anyone else dies, report it immediately!
그리고 다른 사람이 죽으면, 즉시 신고하세요!
Yes, sir!
네, 선생님!
Damn it.
젠장.
You little…
너 좀…
You fucking bastard.
이 빌어먹을 놈.
Are you trying to screw me over?
나를 망치려고 하는 거야?
I warned you, didn't I?
내가 경고했지, 그렇지?
I told you to get that damn kid transferred or whatever
내가 그 빌어먹을 애를 데려오라고 했잖아 양도든 뭐든
to keep him out of trouble.
그를 곤경에 빠뜨리지 않기 위해.
Hey, look at this mess.
이봐, 이 엉망진창 좀 봐.
You brought this on yourself.
당신은 이것을 스스로 가져 왔습니다.
Get it?
알겠어요?
PERSONAL RECORD
개인 기록
- BAEK KIHYUN - MALE
-백기현 - 남성
Baek Kihyun,
백기현,
it's been a long time.
오랜만이에요.
We haven't seen each other since graduation?
우리는 서로를 본 적이 없습니다 졸업하고부터?
Don't cut corners just because you know me.
모서리를 자르지 마십시오 당신이 나를 알고 있기 때문에.
Do what you always do.
항상 하던 일을 하세요.
INVESTIGATION OFFICER NAM SANGUK
조사관 남상국
Still cocky as ever, huh?
아직도 여전히 건방지죠?
Because you graduated top of our class?
당신이 우리 반에서 수석으로 졸업했기 때문에?
So you think everyone's beneath you?
그럼 모두가 당신 밑에 있다고 생각하시나요?
You're Security Command now, but you haven't changed.
당신은 이제 보안 사령부입니다. 하지만 당신은 변하지 않았습니다.
Cut the smart-ass act and proceed.
똑똑한 행동을 중단하고 진행하십시오.
There must be a reason they sent you.
당신을 보낸 이유가 있을 겁니다.
Well…
음…
I heard you testified your company commander
나는 당신이 증언했다고 들었습니다. 당신의 중대장
shot down the transfer request for Private Hong.
이적요청을 격추하다 홍 일병에게.
Is that true?
그게 사실인가요?
I don't make things up.
나는 일을 꾸미지 않습니다.
I said exactly what happened.
나는 정확히 무슨 일이 일어났는지 말했다.
You know,
아시다시피,
you really haven't changed a bit, have you?
너 정말 하나도 안 변했어 조금, 그렇죠?
Still condescending as fuck when you don't know shit.
아직도 존나 거만하게 굴어 모르는 일이 있을 때.
Your company commander?
당신 회사 사령관?
Apparently, his uncle's the Vice Minister of Foreign Affairs,
분명히 그의 삼촌의 외교부 차관,
and his father runs Myeongjung Construction.
그리고 그의 아버지는 달려간다 명중건설.
The best way to clean up this mess
이 혼란을 정리하는 가장 좋은 방법
is for someone to take responsibility and step down.
누군가를 위한 거야 책임을 지고 물러나겠습니다.
But it's never going to be your commander.
하지만 그 사람은 결코 당신의 사령관이 될 수 없습니다.
That's what I'm trying to tell you.
그것이 내가 당신에게 말하려는 것입니다.
Get it?
알겠어요?
You know what hits me hard every single day at Security Command?
무엇이 나를 힘들게 하는지 알잖아 보안사령부에서 매일?
No matter how great you are,
당신이 아무리 훌륭하더라도,
you can't do jack on your own.
잭은 혼자서는 할 수 없어요.
So stop acting like you're the only one with integrity and rewrite your statement.
그러니 당신이 유일한 사람인 것처럼 행동하지 마세요 정직하게 진술서를 다시 작성하십시오.
It's not too late.
너무 늦지 않았습니다.
If you cooperate now, I can keep you in uniform.
지금 협력한다면, 나는 당신에게 유니폼을 입힐 수 있습니다.
Hey.
여기요.
What are academy buddies for?
학원 친구는 무엇을 위한 것인가요?
We should cover each other's asses, right?
우리는 서로의 엉덩이를 덮어야 하는 거죠, 그렇죠?
So from now on, you just need to do what I tell you.
그럼 지금부터, 내가 말하는 대로만 하면 돼.
All right?
괜찮은?
You mean you want me to take the hit instead of ruining my commander's career?
내가 공격을 받기를 원한다는 뜻이군요 내 지휘관의 경력을 망치는 대신?
Hey.
여기요.
I testified the way I did because I knew you were going to do this.
나는 내가 한 방식으로 간증했다. 왜냐하면 나는 당신이 이 일을 할 것이라는 것을 알고 있었기 때문입니다.
What?
무엇?
I don't want to ruin my own career either.
나도 내 경력을 망치고 싶지 않아요.
Tell him, if he wants to use his uncle for an easy out,
그가 사용하고 싶다면 그에게 말하세요 그의 삼촌은 외출을 쉽게 하고,
he'd better rethink making me the scapegoat and handle it properly.
그 사람은 나를 만드는 걸 다시 생각하는 게 나을 거야 희생양을 잡아서 제대로 처리하세요.
I'm not going down alone.
나는 혼자 내려가지 않을 것이다.
Sir!
선생님!
Someone's here to see you, sir.
당신을 만나러 온 사람이 있습니다.
He's in the visiting area.
그는 방문 지역에 있습니다.
How can I believe you?
내가 어떻게 당신을 믿을 수 있습니까?
It's hard to believe, isn't it?
믿기 어렵습니다. 그렇지 않나요?
But you know as well as I do, Mr. Baek Kihyun.
하지만 너도 나만큼 잘 알지, 백기현 선생님.
The fact that Mr. Baek Kitae has
백기태씨가 가지고 있다는 사실은
that much power at his age.
그 나이에 그 정도의 힘.
Well, that doesn't just happen on its own.
글쎄, 그것은 저절로 일어나는 것이 아닙니다.
Your sister.
당신의 여동생.
Ms. Baek Soyeong is helping him with the business.
백소영씨가 도와주고 있어요 사업과 함께.
If I arrest Baek Kitae,
백기태를 체포한다면
your sister goes to prison,
네 여동생은 감옥에 가고,
and you, Mr. Baek Kihyun, might be forced out of the army too.
그리고 백기현 선생님, 군대에서도 쫓겨날 수도 있다.
Before that happens, you should talk to her and get her to confess.
그 전에 얘기부터 해야지 그녀에게 다가가서 고백하게 하세요.
If you could have taken my brother down so easily, you wouldn't be here right now.
내 동생을 쓰러뜨릴 수 있었다면 너무 쉽게, 당신은 지금 여기에 없을 것입니다.
The fact that you even had to come to me
니가 나한테 오기까지 했다는 사실
means you're in a tight spot, right?
당신이 곤경에 처했다는 뜻이죠, 그렇죠?
So bad that you, a prosecutor, are threatening me.
검사인 당신이 안타깝네요. 나를 위협하고 있어요.
You're a lot like your brother.
당신은 당신의 형제와 매우 흡사합니다.
But there's one thing you don't know.
하지만 당신이 모르는 한 가지가 있습니다.
I'm never going to give up.
나는 결코 포기하지 않을 것이다.
I'll make sure Baek Kitae faces the law and pays for what he's done.
백기태가 반드시 법에 맞서도록 할게요 그리고 그가 한 일에 대한 대가를 치르게 됩니다.
Mr. Baek Kihyun!
백기현 선생님!
Think carefully!
신중하게 생각해보세요!
What's your plan?
당신의 계획은 무엇입니까?
How long will you let Jang Geonyoung run loose?
언제까지 놔두실 건가요? 장건영이 쫓겨났나?
I heard from the prosecution's Inspection Division.
검찰측으로부터 들었습니다. 검사과.
They say they can't hold his team much longer.
버틸 수 없다고 하더군요 그의 팀은 훨씬 더 길다.
Okay?
좋아요?
If we go at him half-baked, it'll be worse than doing nothing.
우리가 반쯤 구운 그에게 가면, 아무것도 하지 않는 것보다 더 나쁠 것입니다.
So what are you thinking?
그래서 당신은 무엇을 생각하고 있습니까?
I'll handle it.
제가 처리하겠습니다.
Hey, you…
이봐, 너…
Just tell me, okay?
그냥 말해봐, 알았지?
Handle it how exactly?
정확히 어떻게 처리하나요?
Come in.
들어오세요.
I'm sorry to interrupt, sir.
방해해서 미안해요 선생님.
It's urgent.
긴급합니다.
What the hell are you looking at?
도대체 무엇을 보고 있는 걸까요?
You telling me to leave?
나한테 떠나라고 했어?
Spit it out.
뱉어내세요.
What is it? Just tell me.
그것은 무엇입니까? 그냥 말해 보세요.
I'm afraid there's a problem with your brother.
문제가 있는 것 같아요 네 동생이랑.
Security Command's launched an investigation,
보안사령부 출범 조사,
and it's not looking good.
그리고 별로 안 좋아 보이는데.
What?
무엇?
Who's here? The KCIA? Baek's brother…
여기 누구야? KCIA요? 백현 오빠...
What are you talking about, idiot?
무슨 소리 하는 거야, 바보야?
Well, who are you?
글쎄, 당신은 누구입니까?
Stand up straight.
똑바로 일어서세요.
Back to your senses?
정신을 차리셨나요?
Yes.
예.
Go get Baek Kihyun.
가서 백기현을 데려오세요.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
How did you hear about it?
그 소식을 어떻게 들었나요?
Did you think I wouldn't find out if you kept quiet?
내가 알아내지 못할 거라고 생각했나요? 조용히 있었다면?
I can handle this on my own.
나는 이것을 혼자서 처리할 수 있다.
Handle it how exactly?
정확히 어떻게 처리하나요?
I said, I'll handle it on my own!
내가 직접 처리하겠다고 했어요!
I told you.
내가 말했잖아.
If you're angry at reality, get stronger.
현실에 분노한다면 더 강해지세요.
If you don't want to be looked down on, strike first.
당신이되고 싶지 않다면 무시하고 먼저 공격하십시오.
If someone blocks your path, get rid of them.
누군가가 당신의 길을 막는다면, 그들을 제거하십시오.
How many times have I told you
내가 몇 번이나 말했지?
that guys with power run the world at the end of the day?
저 힘 있는 놈들 하루가 끝나면 세상을 운영할 것인가?
If you're done, I'll be going now.
다 끝났으면 지금 가겠습니다.
Stop.
멈추다.
You cocky little…
건방진 꼬마야...
Your company commander will be the one forced out, not you.
당신의 회사 사령관은 강제로 쫓겨난 사람은 당신이 아니라요.
Security Command will have an opening next month, so get ready.
보안사령부가 개회할 예정입니다 다음 달이니까 준비하세요.
This is power.
이것이 힘이다.
Got it?
알았어요?
I'm going to Vietnam next week.
저는 다음주에 베트남에 갑니다.
What the hell would you go there for?
도대체 무엇 때문에 거기로 갈 건가요?
That "power" you always talk about.
당신이 늘 말하는 그 '힘'.
I figured I'd try to earn some myself.
나는 나 자신을 좀 벌려고 노력할 것이라고 생각했습니다.
All you need to do is what I tell you!
당신이해야 할 일은 내가 말하는 것뿐입니다!
I can take care of myself!
나는 나 자신을 돌볼 수 있다!
You little…
너 좀…
So I want you
그래서 나는 당신을 원해요
to please just get your own act together.
그냥 함께 행동해 보세요.
PROSECUTOR JANG GEONYOUNG
장건영 검사
Before you wreck my life and Soyeong's too.
당신이 내 인생을 망치기 전에 그리고 소영이도 그렇고.
Ms. Oh.
오 씨.
What are you doing out here?
여기서 뭐하고 있어요?
Mr. Jang, where have you been?
장 선생님, 어디 계셨나요?
I went to see Baek Kihyun.
백기현을 만나러 갔어요.
Baek Kihyun?
백기현?
Things must've been rough.
상황이 힘들었나 봐요.
No, it's okay.
아니요, 괜찮아요.
Appreciate the effort. Let's get inside.
노력에 감사드립니다. 안으로 들어가자.
Well,
글쎄,
why did you go to see Baek Kihyun, sir?
백기현 씨는 왜 만나러 가셨나요?
Thought I'd stir up Baek Kitae too.
나도 백기태를 휘저어볼까 생각했다.
We've got to hit back just as hard as he hit us.
우리는 반격해야 해 그가 우리를 때린 것만큼 세게 때렸어요.
So you're not giving up?
그럼 포기하지 않을 건가요?
Why would I give up?
내가 왜 포기하겠어요?
It's my job to catch criminals.
범인을 잡는 것이 내 일이다.
You haven't eaten yet, right? Let's eat first and get our strength back.
아직 식사도 안 하신 거죠? 일단 밥먹고 힘내자.
Where's Mr. Kim?
김 선생님은 어디 계시나요?
I'm not sure.
잘 모르겠습니다.
He said he'd be here soon.
그는 곧 여기에 올 것이라고 말했습니다.
But I think we ran out of rice.
그런데 밥이 부족한 것 같아요.
Should I cook some ramyeon?
라면 끓여볼까?
Shoot. We're out of ramyeon, too.
사격. 저희도 라면이 떨어졌어요.
I'll run out and get some.
나가서 좀 사올게요.
Oh, no. I'll go, sir.
안 돼. 제가 갈게요, 선생님.
I'll be right back.
곧 돌아올게요.
Take care.
잘 지내세요.
Oh, man.
아, 이런.
It started raining.
비가 내리기 시작했습니다.
I won't live as cattle.
나는 소로 살지 않을 것이다.
I'll be the one with power.
나는 힘을 가진 사람이 될 것이다.
I'll make the herd kneel before me,
나는 무리를 내 앞에 무릎을 꿇게 만들 것이다.
drag down anyone more powerful than me,
나보다 더 강한 사람을 끌어내려라.
and change the world in the end.
그리고 결국 세상을 바꾸게 됩니다.
-Ms. Oh, you're here alone? -Yes.
-Ms. 아, 여기 혼자 오셨나요? -예.
-Where's Mr. Jang? -He went to get some ramyeon.
- 장 선생님은 어디 계시나요? -라면을 사러 갔어요.
Hey, the water's boiling.
안녕하세요, 물이 끓고 있습니다.
Man, I'm exhausted.
아, 나 지쳤어.
That's just the way it is.
그것이 바로 그 방법입니다.
The world has always been
세상은 언제나 그랬다.
a battlefield for the powerful.
강자들의 전쟁터.
Translated by Yoonjung Song
옮긴이: 송윤정